

Sibasis Mukherjee Cloud DevOps Engineer









- 📤 Mittenwalder Straße 30, 10961 Berlin
- mukherjee.sibasis@yahoo.com
- ****** +49 15736584093, +47 47725263
- sibasismukherjee.github.io

OBJECTIVE

A Multi-Tasking result-oriented and focused consultant with a keen eye on efficiency and quality. Having rich experience in developing and consulting DevOps processes for over 6 years in Banking and Financial Domain. Rich Cloud Consulting experience with enterprise customers on their cloud adoption and acceleration strategies. Developing and Designing fault-tolerant, high-performing and resilient applications and platforms that scale with trending business requirements. Automating event based operation tools that provide deep insight and maintenance of heavy production workloads on AWS. Looking for a challenging and an exciting opportunity to hone my skills with DevOps and consulting on cloud.

EDUCATION

Aug 2009 - June 2013

West Bengal University of Technology

Bachelor of Technology in Information Technology

EXPERIENCE

Since Sept 2019

Cloudreach, Berlin, Germany

Cloud Systems Developer

- Development of a highly available, fault tolerant and optimized API Platform on
- Consult for scaling a multinational automobile giant's Financial Services Group. Providing a robust platform where contributors can develop on cloud.
- Take charge of DevOps Processes of the platform that can scale to multi-regions spanning multiple continents.
- Develop tools and libraries that can accelerate SDLC processes on the said API Platform.

April 2017 - August 2019

Tata Consultancy Services, Bergen, Norway

Cloud DevOps Engineer

• Took part in a greenfield project to develop a customer centric Banking Application on AWS.

- Consulting for a major Nordic Bank to develop DevOps Processes for the backend platform.
- Code all the Infra components from greenfield to production.
- Drive the Cost Optimization initiative cross project to enhance the architecture further after Go-Live. And drive the Well Architected Review and it's action-points t further strengthen the platform.
- Drive CI/CD initiatives for multiple projects for both frontends and backends.

July 2015 - May 2017

Tata Consultancy Services, Frankfurt, Germany

DevOps Engineer

- Consult with a German Clearing House's new Product initiative team to setup automation processes.
- Develop test-suites and automation pipelines to cover various SDLC's.
- Leverage open source tools to setup the processes
- Support the Operational workloads and Maintain them for bugs and patches.

Mar 2014 - July 2015

Tata Consultancy Services, Pune, India

Software Engineer

• Provide Offshore Development for a German Clearing House for their upcoming projects.

SKILLS

Tools and Softwares

- Docker
- AWS Managed Services
- Sceptre

- AWS CDK
- Hashicorp Vault
- Serverless Application
- CI/CD tools: Concourse,
 Ops Tools: OpsGenie, ELK
 Agile Tools: Atlassian Jenkins, XLDeploy
 - stack, Dynatrace, Splunk and Datadog
 - Toolchain
 - Security Tools: Dome9, CloudCustodian, Wapiti,
 - GuardDuty

Languages

JavaScript

Python

Java

Certifications



